

Teun Zengerink

Senior Frontend Developer

Personal details

Address: Van Bossestraat 48-2

1041 KA Amsterdam

The Netherlands

Email address: <u>teun@cyberpeaks.nl</u>
Phone number: +31 (0)6 5471 6572

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tzengerink/

GitHub: https://github.com/tzengerink/
Company: https://www.cyberpeaks.nl/
Personal: https://teun.zengerink.com/



Software engineer with over 13 years of professional experience. Passionate about developing creative solutions that have an impact on its users and society. Motivated to guide organisations in implementing Agile/Scrum practices, mentor junior developers and improve engineering processes. Admired by peers for being reliable, critical, authentic, outspoken, opinionated and emphatic.

Developer Experience

Languages & Frameworks

TypeScript, JavaScript, React, React-Native, Angular, Redux, RxJS, GraphQL, Sass, Less, Node, Next.js, Jest, Yarn, Lerna, Webpack, Tailwind, D3.js

| Tools & Platforms | Design & Project Management |
|-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|------------------------------------------------------------|
| GitHub, GitLab, Azure DevOps, Kubernetes, Jenkins, CircleCI, Amazon Web Service, Microsoft Azure | Scrum, Jira, Confluence, Trello, Figma, Adobe Photoshop |



Work Experience

Senior Frontend Developer

MyWheels, March 2022 - July 2023

Creating new frontend functionalities for mobile app, website and back-office application.

- Introduce automated testing and stricter TypeScript compiler options to increase code quality, maintainability and reliability.
- Assist growing development team in introducing the Scrum philosophy to add more predictability in creation of valuable output.
- Tech used: TypeScript, React, React-Native, Next.js, Jest, GraphQL,
 Yarn, Webpack, Tailwind, GitLab, Jenkins, Jira, Figma, Scrum

Senior Frontend Developer

Rabobank, October 2021 - February 2022

Developing user interfaces for the onboarding flows that provide a fluent experience for new customers in opening a bank account.

- Improve state management by introducing Redux to produce consistent application behavior, while also reducing code duplication.
- Implement stricter TypeScript compiler options to create stronger guarantees of program correctness and easier code collaboration.
- Tech used: TypeScript, Angular, Redux, RxJS, Sass, Yarn, Jest, Azure DevOps, Microsoft Azure, Jira, Scrum

Senior Frontend Developer

GrandVision, January 2021 - July 2021

Building a whitelabel frontend for use in a MACH architecture serving eCommerce sites for multiple operating companies (Pearl, EyeWish, VisionExpress and others).

- Coordinate with Product Owner and Business Analyst to validate requirements and define technical approach for its implementation.
- Mentor and assist (junior) frontend developers in the team.
- Tech used: TypeScript, React, Redux, Sass, GraphQL, Jest, Yarn,
 Next.js, Lerna, Webpack, GitHub, Microsoft Azure, Jira, Scrum

Photography Internship

Takeaway.com, February 2020 - July 2020

Product Owner

Usabilla, August 2018 - December 2019

Accountable for iOS and Android SDK as well as the React-Native, Cordova and Xamarin bridges for those SDKs.

- Revamped the user interface of the forms while thoroughly testing it to meet accessibility standards.
- Improved the flow for enriching feedback items by attaching screenshots and camera images.
- Made use of design sprints, customer journey maps, problem area definitions, personas, brainstorms and validation interviews.



Senior Fullstack Software Engineer

Usabilla, January 2016 - August 2018

Responsible for creating well architected and maintainable code that meets the described requirements and end user expectations.

- Collaborated closely with the Product Owner, UX/UI designers and other engineers.
- Mentored junior engineers and participated in discussions with designers to create the best overall experience.
- Tech used: TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Angular, Jest, Sass, Node, PHP, Python, Symfony, D3.js, AWS, Jira, Scrum

Fullstack Developer

TROI Studio, December 2010 - January 2016

Create an e-learning platform used by Nike, TNT and SAP.

Tech used: JavaScript, Angular, Less, Python, PHP, Flask, MySQL,
 AWS, Linux, Docker

Fullstack Developer

Studenten.net, January 2010 - December 2010

Responsible for the maintenance of vacancy websites for USG People.

- Tech used: JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, .NET

Education

Professional Photographer

Fotoacademie Amsterdam, February 2018 - September 2020

Bachelor Arts, Culture and Media

Rijksuniversiteit Groningen, September 2006 - June 2009

Bachelor Business Administration and Computer Science

Hanzehogeschool Groningen, September 2002 - June 2006

Certification

Certified Kubernetes Application Developer

Cloud Native Computing Foundation, August 2021

Certified Scrum Master

Xebia, January 2017

Languages

- Dutch (Native)
- English (Fluent)

